#### Mikhail Garber

25233 SE 42<sup>nd</sup> Dr., Issaquah, WA 98029 (425) 233-0373 mikhail@garbercentral.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/mikhailgarber

# **OBJECTIVE: Principal / Senior Developer / Technical Project Lead / Software Architect**

## **SKILLS:**

25+ years of hands-on development experience. 20+ years of Java. 20+ years of Oracle. Object-oriented design and programming. Web Services, Service Oriented Architecture, micro services, REST. Distributed systems, highly available architectures. Database and schema design, administration and programming. Public API design and implementation. Cloud Computing, expert on Amazon Web Services. IAAS and PAAS. Big Data, ML and recommendation systems. Full, agile or traditional software development lifecycle. Building solid teams, mentoring and education of junior developers. Task estimates, project and budget planning, formal leadership and management. Workflow applications and rule engines. Application servers. Search-based application and solutions. ORM, XML and data binding. Messaging and async. Monitoring and eventing. Strong cryptography and network security.

### **KEYWORDS:**

Java, Oracle, Spring GraphQL, Hibernate, MVC, JMS, JSP/JSTL, JDBC, PL/SQL, stored procedures, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, NoSQL, REST APIs, Hbase, MongoDB, Hadoop, Spark, Pig, Lucene, Solr, Elasticsearch, Tomcat, Jboss, Jetty, Apache, LXC containers, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, S3, EC2, ELB, RDS, SQS, Azure, Linux, Windows, Ant, Maven, Gradle, Junit, Jenkins, CI, CircleCI, Ruby, C/C++, nodejs, typescript

## **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS:**

BS in Mathematics and Computer Science
1992-1994 Lawrence Technological University, Detroit, Michigan
BS in Applied Information Systems
1986-1991 Industrial University, Baku, Azerbaijan
Sun Certified Architect for J2EE platform
Sun Certified Programmer for Java 2 platform
Published industry author and patent holder
Naturalized US citizen, employment is fully authorized

### **EXPERIENCE:**

**2017-present Senior Software Development Engineer** *Amazon, Seattle, WA* Undisclosed Initiatives, Devices / Digital Initiatives, Prime Air drones. Delivered diverse set of successful projects. Services, asynchronous workflows, e-commerce, large scale integration, gaming, video, UIs. Mentored and organized junior developers. Assisted business development with strategy and estimates. Java, nodejs, GraphQL, AWS.

#### Mikhail Garber

25233 SE 42<sup>nd</sup> Dr., Issaquah, WA 98029 (425) 233-0373 mikhail@garbercentral.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/mikhailgarber

# 2016-2017 Senior Principal Software Engineer Concur, Bellevue, WA

Led several initiatives converting large legacy applications to smaller, more manageable services. Integrated disperse distributed workflows. Designed and developed innovative loosely-connected lightweight messaging framework aimed at rapid development of business logic decoupled from messaging substrates. Java, REST, Springboot, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS.

**2014-2016 Principal Software Engineer – Social Intelligence** *Salesforce.com, Seattle, WA* As part of Salesforce Chatter teams ("Facebook for business"), worked on discovery, recommendation and delivery of relevant content to users of leading enterprise social network and Salesforce Communities. Used traditional databases and Big Data tools to extract and process variety of signals from user's posts, likes, follows, comments etc. to identify and expose trending topics and other relevant information and provide recommendations. Promoted culture of unit testing and many other improvements of the development process.

**2012-2014 Senior Program Manager** *Microsoft, Redmond, Washington*As part of Microsoft Autopilot, designed, evaluated and analyzed very large scale logging, tracing and monitoring systems in Bing and Windows Azure environments. Identified commonality between disperse systems and teams, facilitated emergence of common vision and strategy. Prepared design and requirement documents, developed and validated product features, managed commitments across multiple teams.

**2011-2012 Senior Software Engineer – Global Payments** *Expedia, Bellevue, Washington* Designed and implemented new features and improvements in Expedia's complex SOA environment including Web Services and various internal frameworks. Coordinated development activities with offshore teams, drove agile development processes and improved product release practices.

**2010-2011 Senior Software Engineer** *F5 Networks, Seattle, Washington* Contributed to multiple components of F5 Enterprise Manager product. Responsible for ondevice storage architecture including database-driven storage and free-form search. Implemented collection and processing of per-device performance management statistics, corresponding UI elements, bug fixes and overall improvements.

**2006-2010** Senior Software Development Engineer Amazon.com, Seattle, Washington Engaged in number of challenging projects working on Amazon-size solutions as part of Amazon Payments, Distributed Database Systems and Amazon Web Services teams. Was primary developer of three new Amazon Web Services, including Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) and Amazon Elastic Beanstalk, from conception to public availability. Migrated core business components of Amazon retail website to SOA.

**1991-2010 Multiple Software Engineering and Management Positions**Retail, Airspace, Defense, Government, Travel, Warehousing, Logistics and other industries